# HAYREDDIN TUZEL

SFCC BACKEND DEVELOPER

+49 176 248 855 41

Heilbronn, Germany

## **PROFILE ME**

Since 2015, I am working on web and app programming. In this process, I have been involved in the construction of many websites and web apps by developing or managing teams. I started my career as a contractor developer on a small startup and become the head of engineering between 2014 - 2018. Then I turn my career route on the Salesforce Commerce Cloud path, and I am working as a Senior Salesforce Commerce Cloud developer at Signa Sports United.



I am also a certified Salesforce Commerce Cloud Developer with 4 years of experience.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### DEVELOPER-HEAD OF ENGINEERING / GLOBAL EDUCATION TECHNOLOGY LLC A.K.A TURACOON

2014-2018

I started my career as a contractor developer in Turacoon and continued as head of engineering. While managing a small software team, I also determined all the technological roadmaps on my own.

I took full engineering responsibility for Turacoon's story, which moved from 0 users to thousands of users.

In this process;

- Determination of Devops Architecture,
- Changing the front-end architecture,
- Transition from a monolithic structure to microservice architecture,
- Publishing the mobile application,
- management of sub-brands as Multiple Domains.

I experienced being the manager of all processes on the above.

### SFCC BACKEND DEVELOPER / OSF DIGITAL

2018-2020

As long as worked at OSF, worked as a backend developer. However, due to my previous experience, I occasionally solved front-end tasks, too. I worked with a large project team of approximately 30 members, including FD and BD developers, QAs, and PMs at OSF. In the project where we adopt the Agile technique, we developed multiple features at the same time and fixed bugs.

I developed many features as the main developer. Also, was able to develop some features myself alone. Although I was working in the role of developer, I developed solutions such as tech lead in some sub-projects.

Some of the features I worked on in this process were as follows;

- Subscription (SFCC and Zuora integration)
- Wishlist
- Loyalty Points and a lot of customization on SFCC's
- default promotion / campaign system
- Refund
- Worldpay 3DS version 2 (3DS Flex)
- Ownership (Another big integration with 3th party)
- Creating of some jobs for importing and exporting
- products, customers etc.
- And bug fix in almost all areas of SFCC

By working on these features, I gained experience on these submodules of SFCC:

- Pipelines / Controllers
- Checkout Flow
- Promotion/Campaigns and Coupons
- Inhs
- Service Integrations
- SFRA
- Orders
- Products
- FD Javascript

My general responsibilities at OF digital are:

- Code implementation,
- Creation of pull requests,
- Reviewing of Pull Requests,
- Analysis of customer requests and finding solutions,
- Giving estimation for customer's requests,
- Creating technical documents,
- Creating guides for our customers' business team,
- Reporting to my Project Manager,
- Verification of the code I have implemented in CI environments

#### SENIOR SFCC BACKEND DEVELOPER / INTERNETSTORES/SIGNA SPORTS UNITED

2020 - PRESENT

Currently, I am working on Internetstores as a Senior SFCC backend developer. Here, we are working as two different teams. My team is working on Purchase and engagement that includes these SFCC submodules;

- Checkout Flow,
- Account Pages,
- Wishlists and Product Lists,
- Shipping and Payment Methods,
- Leadtimes calculations,
- Service Integrations,
- Campaigns, Promotions, Coupons, Gift Cards,
- Tracking,
- Order Management

Sure, we are also collaborating with other teams and getting some tasks from other areas of SFCC. Also, we are continuously migrating some legacy (PHP-based) e-commerce websites to SFCC.

Also, my main responsibilities are:

- Implementing new requirements and requests from the business team and defining implementation steps,
- Meeting with business team and analyzing requests,
- Finding solutions for complex requirements,
- Preparing documentation,
- · Code review,
- Contributing to the planning of Sprints,
- Handling of Releases and Deployments
- Code and Data replication between different SFCC
- Instances
- Migrating old e-commerce websites to SFCC

## **EDUCATION/SKILLS**

**COMPUTER ENGINEERING**WITH HONOUR DEGREE (1st)

NAVAL ACADEMY, TURKEY

2009-2013

• Salesforce Commerce Cloud

Nodejs

Javascript

React/Vuejs

PHP

Python